#### Contact

abhishek2mx3@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/abhishek8899 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Competitive Programming Machine Learning Software Development

# **Abhishek Mathur**

SWE Intern @ Stealth Startup | CSE @ IIITH'21 Hyderabad

## Summary

I am a senior year software engineering student pursuing B.Tech in Computer Science at IIIT Hyderabad. My interests revolve around deep learning and neural networks. I have experience working with CNNs and NLP. Recently, I had worked on "Multimodal Image Hashtag Generation" project which aimed to derive hashtags from any Instagram post which contained text, image or both. I am also passionate about Algorithmic Problem Solving and actively participate in online programming contests on various platforms like Codeforces and Codechef.

# Experience

**IIIT Hyderabad** 

Teaching Assistant

August 2020 - Present (1 month)

- Course: Software Systems Development
- Target audience: Postgraduate students
- Curriculum: Advanced knowledge regarding UNIX tools, SD languages (Bash, Python, JavaScript), databases and networking.

#### Stealth Startup

Software Engineer

May 2020 - August 2020 (4 months)

- Backend: Worked with spring framework on microservice based architecture to integrate end-2-end flow of third party API services.
- Frontend: Worked on design testing using Jest, along with writing regression tests for the react component library.

IIIT Hyderabad

1 year 1 month

Teaching Assistant

January 2020 - March 2020 (3 months)

Hyderabad Area, India

- Course: Introduction to Software Systems
- Target Audience: Undergraduate students
- Curriculum: Working knowledge of tools and processes for building simple software systems.

Member of Student Parliament March 2019 - March 2020 (1 year 1 month)

Hyderabad, Telangana

Software Engineering Research Center, IIIT Hyderabad Researcher

May 2019 - July 2019 (3 months)

Hyderabad Area, India

Worked on credibility assessment and ranking of the web results based on genre credibility and relevance order. Used specific ontologies for calculating relevance score based on webpage content.

Butterfly Edufields Pvt. Ltd.
Software Engineer
August 2018 - October 2018 (3 months)
Hyderabad, Telangana, India

AR developer

Developed two games (Nutrimania and Integer Maze) based on Augmented Reality using Unity 3D (Vuforia) for children aged 6-11 for better learning.

## Education

IIIT Hyderabad

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science · (2017 - 2021)

Cambridge Court High School, Jaipur

 $\cdot$  (2008 - 2017)